[Mr. Frohicky] ...Well,
they try in their own way,
but not one of them
I would consider a fine chef.
Kai can defrost pizza.
Poorly.
Had lots of time to learn
how to cook
in the Land of Lost Things.
Ton of ingredients
show up there.
I once found a tray
of diced garlic.
Oh, I reeked for a month,
but, mm... delicious!
Well, having you here
has made the part of my job
where I'm expected to be
a Master Chef easier.
[chuckling]
Now, if you could learn
to polish a floor...
Come on, play with us!
Oh, I'm not that healed yet.
I'll just watch you two.
[kids laughing playfully]
Ah, refreshments.
Mm.
Ah, I've been parched.
Glad to you see you
doing so well, Rontu.
We, uh...
had some doubts
you would pull through.
You are not the only one.
I must confess,
I had lost hope myself.
Well, fetid salamander broth
is such a strong,
natural medicine,
it could grow skin
on a Greenbone Warrior!
[chuckling politely] Yes...
though the broth did taste...
[clearing throat] ...fine,
my return was more spiritual.
I spoke to an old love,
and discovered a new purpose.
My work on this plane
is not done.
Nope, pretty sure
it was the broth.
[sniffing] That smells good.
Geo, are you cooking here now?
Yup,
but I have to go out
and buy ingredients,
not wait for a geyser
to burp them up.
Well, apparently,
that's more reliable
than sending Arin's parents off
with a grocery list.
They've been gone for--
[panting]
There was an attack
in the Crossroads!
Some kind of energy monster!
Energy Monster?
Came out of nowhere.
We got people to safety,
but then it just disappeared
as weirdly as it appeared.
Smashed the whole place up.
And this monster kept you
from getting
the fermented beetles why?
No, they did the right thing,
Mr. Frohicky.
But an Energy monster?
Ras stole scrolls
about containing energy.
Maybe the puzzle pieces
are all in a row...
Um, "falling into place."
Ducks are in a row,
pieces fall into place.
I... I knew that.
Did you see the Monster
that attacked,
and where it went?
Saw it?
Dang near blasted my hair off!
Then the thing just evaporated
into thin air.
[scanner warbling]
Not suspicious behavior at all.
[♪♪♪]
[grunting with effort]
[elemental powers shorting]
♪ Lost in the unknown ♪
♪ So much to see ♪
♪ Jump up, kick back
whip around and spin ♪
♪ Together we will rise ♪
♪ Whip around and spin ♪
♪ For what's right ♪♪
[Cole groaning]
[crowd shouting with effort]
Anyone--
ow--
see where that person
in the mask ran off to?
[mumbling uncertainly]
[groaning]
Well, looks like
I stumbled into something
painfully nefarious...
[audible smooching]
Uh...
you two done yet?
You remember everything now?
Not everything.
As soon as that machine
processed,
I got a flood of memories,
but more keep popping up,
and I don't know
what I don't know,
so who knows how many
more memories I'm gonna recall.
But you're back?
I'm back.
So, uh, does that mean
you remember the time
you fought Bolobo
in just your underpants?
That one...
that one's not ringing a bell.
What about when you convinced
a bunch of video game fan boys
to dress up like you,
and talk about
how awesome you were?
Nope.
Not that one either.
Are you sure?
Maybe you just don't want
to remember those stories?
'Cause if I were you,
I'd try to forget them, too.
No, I'm serious.
It feels like my memories
are "healing",
just repopulating my mind.
And who erased your memories
in the first place?
That... I still don't remember,
yet,
but I'm sure it'll--
[gasping] Oh my!
[sobbing uncontrollably]
Uh... you okay, buddy?
Mr. Slowthers!
[sobbing]
Poor Mr. Slowthers.
Who is Mr. Slowthers?
My turtle! [sniffling]
My pet turtle I had
when I was a little kid!
He ran away,
and I couldn't catch up to him!
You couldn't catch up to a...
turtle?
Apparently,
I wasn't very good at running
as a kid, okay?
Leave me alone! [sobbing]
I know getting
your memories back
in weird bursts like this
has got to be a shock,
and I'm sure Mr. Slowthers
found a new safe place
somewhere,
but we gotta do the same.
The Administration is not
going to stop looking for us.
Come on.
[Jay whispering]
I bet these robots
are guarding all the exits.
Curses on whoever
came up with these things.
[Lead Agent, on walkie]
Attention, Delta League,
another
unauthorized energy being
spotted in Region 412.
Assemble a convoy!
Copy that.
[weapons charging]
[revving engines]
Agents, roll out!
[tires squealing]
[distant wailing]
[Lloyd screaming]
[gasping]
[roots stretching]
[♪♪♪]
[gasping]
Wha...
[grunting]
Hello?
Where'd you go?
What was all that?
[wind gusting]
You're not gonna explain
the meaning of that?
It looked like a forest,
sharing energy?
Helping other trees out?
Hello?
What was I supposed to learn
from that?
[tween Lloyd]
Oh, you're gonna find out...
Another version of me?
But... I don't recognize you.
Of course you don't.
I never existed.
I am the you
you skipped over,
but on this journey,
you have to know
everything about your life...
even paths not walked.
My path.
You're the age I skipped over
because of the Tomorrow's Tea.
The age when I was
supposed to hear
the calling
of the Whispering Wood.
Pleased to finally... meet you.
[Euphrasia] Uh, is this right?
I don't feel the balance you--
Arin?
Sorry, I just...
He's been in there all night.
I'm sure he's fine.
Okay, not sure,
but isn't that
why we're training?
To try not to focus
on what's out of our control?
Yeah. Okay.
So your stance is slightly off.
The twist shouldn't
put pressure on your knee,
you'll get injured that way.
It should come from your core,
like this...
Arin,
I notice you have red streaks
in your tornado.
Why is that?
Uh...
No one else has them?
Is that weird?
I've never
encountered it before.
Is my Spinjitzu corrupted
or something?
Did training with Ras
do something bad to me?
I'm sure there's no reason
to be alarmed.
I'd just like to study it more--
[crowd of Acona chittering]
The Acona?
[chittering urgently]
I'm getting the sense
they want us to go with them.
Are we going to just
leave Lloyd?
We'll come back,
but if these beings need help,
Lloyd would want us
to help them.
[tires squealing]
We're here looking into reports
of a monster
on an unlicensed rampage.
Did you report a monster?
Because there's clearly
no ongoing rampage.
Filing a false report
is a severe policy violation,
punishable by being made
to fill out many reports
about the false report.
Do you have anything to say
in your defense?
[Lead Loyalist]
Here's the situation--
I'm taking control
of your convoy.
You've got one chance
to give your vehicles to me.
If not,
I take them by force,
which will go badly for you.
Ha!
Look, not only are you unarmed,
and badly outnumbered,
but you've clearly got no idea
who you're dealing with.
We're from The Administration!
[Lead Loyalist] I warned you.
[snapping fingers]
Huah!
[charging weapons]
[Lead Loyalist]
You're the one with no idea--
no idea how many
of our secret society
have infiltrated
every organization
across the Merged Lands.
Bonnie, no!
You love stamping C-01 permits!
You always smile--
[Loyalist #1] I was faking it,
every single time.
[Lead Loyalist] Attack!
[blasting and shouting]
Ah!
Ugh! Ah!
[Nya]
We've gotta get out there!
Which side would we even join?
We need to see
how this plays out.
[Kai] He's right.
Let's find out what's going on.
[Lead Agent] Agents, retreat!
[yelping in panic]
[Lead Loyalist]
We've got what we need.
[whistling]
Mech Drivers,
you know what to do!
[smashing]
[Lead Loyalist] Success!
All hail the Good Empress!
"Good Empress"?
As in Beatrix,
the whacked-out,
power-hungry maniac?
She sounds kinda fun.
-No.
-She's not.
[Lead Loyalist] Come!
We must find the weapon piece!
[Nya] Weapon? Great...
Last time Beatrix got her hands
on a super weapon,
she triggered a world-ending
series of MergeQuakes!
That was her?
That was messed up!
Whatever this new "weapon" is,
we have to keep it
out of her hands.
[chittering urgently]
[blasts sizzling]
[chittering in distress]
[snarling]
[growling]
[bellowing]
[branches cracking]
[foliage crumbling]
Ninja... Go!
[bellowing]
[Zane] Ah!
[snarling]
[gasping]
Aw...
[leaves crumbling]
[bellowing]
[♪♪♪]
How can a tree
be growing underground
with no sunlight?
-It's--
-[Jay] It's madness.
The Land of Madness!
[Lead Loyalist] This is it.
Behold!
A portion of
the Weapon of Desolation!
The Good Empress
is one step closer
to making her triumphant return!
[Loyalists cheering]
[Lead Loyalist] Pack it up!
We move.
[laughing loudly]
[laughter muffled]
[Jay laughing uncontrollably]
[slightly muffled,
still very loud]
[laughter reverberating]
[Kai whispering]
What are you doing?
Hee-hee-he hit every branch
on the way down!
[cackling]
[Nya] What?!
Ninja are here!
[weapon charging]
[laughing]
I'm sorry, I can't help it!
A memory just suddenly hit me!
This time, I hid Cole's cake
at the top of a tree!
He slipped and fell,
and hit every single branch
on the way down!
-H'ah!
-H'yah!
[laughing]
[chuckling]
That was pretty funny.
[Nya] H'yah!
[Lead Loyalist] Cover my back!
[Nya] Huah! H'yah!
[Kai] Ooh-ah! H'ah!
H'yah!
I'll take that, thank you!
[power surging]
[Kai screaming]
[screams echoing]
Ah!
[Nya] Oof!
-[Jay] Nya!
-[Nya] I'm fine!
They're getting away!
[activating device]
-[energy detonating]
-[Ninja] Ah!
[slamming force field]
[frustrated grunting]
What happened to you
back there?
[Kai] I touched that thing,
and my body was flooded
with uncontrollable
Elemental Energy.
Real weird.
Whatever
a "Weapon of Desolation" is,
we can't let it get to Beatrix!
[Arc Dragon stomping]
[thudding of battle]
[foliage crumbling]
[monster snarling]
[Acona chittering]
[Arin] Ah!
[gasping]
[chittering]
Huah!
Ugh!
That kinda worked.
[Arin]
If I could do it faster...
Hold it, I got an idea!
When I say when,
toss me rocks!
Now!
It's working.
Keep 'em coming!
[bellowing]
[Zane] H'ah!
[Zane grunting with effort]
Huah!
[Arin] Phew!
[gasping in exhaustion]
[groaning]
Arin!
That was beyond
all predictive models.
No one has ever used spinjitzu
that way.
It shouldn't even be possible.
[sighing] I need a nap.
The monsters have returned
to an energy state.
They will come back,
and there's no telling
if Arin will be able
to stop them again.
[bellowing wearily]
Lloyd is our only hope.
If he doesn't succeed
in his trial,
the Whispering Wood
will be lost.
[♪♪♪]
[Wyldfyre] I'm not saying
you're the coolest dragon
I've ever seen now, Riyu,
but you're not not the coolest
dragon I've ever seen!
[replying
in grumbling language]
[grumbling language]
[roaring]
Whoa-ho!
But all that energy
he absorbed.
Are you sure he's okay?
Let me answer your question
with a question.
How many times
do I need to tell you
I'm not a dragon doctor?
All that Elemental Energy
must be what triggered
Riyu's new form.
Still doesn't explain
who released the monster
from its cage
or why?
It has to be
that masked guy I chased, right?
But who's under the mask?
Someone who knew
the airship's layout.
One of the Explorers?
No, that makes no sense.
The Explorers were desperate
to haul that monster
back to Ninjago,
and put it on display.
Why would one of them
release it?
[blowing raspberry]
Nothing those weirdos do
makes sense.
Speaking of...
look who's here.
I say, if you still want
a ride back to Ninjago,
we will be leaving forthwith.
Yes.
Ever since someone--
[Riyu grunting innocently]
--destroyed our specimen,
there's no point in staying
in this benighted
hayseed village.
Best return
to the Explorer's Clubhouse
and await another chance
to secure a glorious legacy.
Can't get a decent cuppa
round here anyway.
Peasants.
We do still need to get back
to the other Ninja
as quickly as we can.
We just need to resupply,
then we'll be on our way.
[Umbrasylvan Grand Inquisitor]
No, you will not!
Who are you supposed to be?
Some kind of headwear salesman?
[blowing trumpet fanfare]
Presenting...
the Grand Inquisitor
Of Umbrasylvis!
Outsiders!
Nothing good ever comes
from outsiders!
Well, that's just nonsense.
If we Explorers
had never come,
you'd never have been discovered
by anyone.
Where would you be then?
Someone released a monster
on purpose
to wreak havoc in our fair town!
Umbrasylvis shall be
on total lockdown
until we determine who it was!
The brigand must pay!
You don't understand.
We need to get back to--
No one leaves here
until someone is punished--
So proclaims
the Grand Inquisitor!
[crowd of citizens cheering]
[♪♪♪]
[knocking on gate]
Senator Tartigrade!
Always nice to see you,
but this is a strange hour
for a visit.
These are strange times,
Mr. Frohicky.
I need to talk to the Ninja.
My apologies,
they are currently
in parts unknown.
Cole's the only one in town,
but he's out
investigating reports
of an energy monster.
An energy monster?
Where?
The Crossroads.
Wow.
That's exactly why I'm here.
Imperium was invaded
by a strange energy creature.
It caused a lot of damage,
then disappeared.
I was hoping the Ninja
could help us figure out
what it was.
I'll tell Cole
as soon as he returns.
Thank you,
we need the help.
Imperium's infrastructure
can't handle
more attacks like that.
[knocking in code]
Bigger than I thought.
I should've brought back-up.
[Dr. LaRow]
Yes, you should have...
...but you didn't.
Stun him,
but keep him alive.
[stun beam crackling]
A Ninja on our trail.
How predictable.
[♪♪♪]